In this lecture we will understand the process of installing SSL certificates on Dockerize.net apps.
Let us understand what is SSL, an SSL certificate full form, secure socket layer, also known as TLS certificate full form, transport layer security,
is an internet security protocol that encrypts data between a browser and a website,
does ensuring protection of data from hackers. When an app has an SSL certificate,
then it uses HTTPS connection instead of HTTP connection. The browser will now show padlock icon in green color.
In this image you can see the green padlock icon on the browser that signifies the website is using
an SSL certificate. So this website is safe to use. The green certificate is actually an SSL certificate
which is also known as TLS certificate. Now moving to our Dockerized app, you can see it is not using
any SSL certificate. It is opening on HTTP protocol. You can check this by copying the address bar
in the browser and pasting it on a notepad to see HTTP in the URL. If we open the HTTPS
version of this URL, then you can see the browser shows error. Let us configure SSL on this app.
.net provides a development certificate which can be used in our scenario. Who .net DevSerts command,
we will create this development certificate for our app. Note that we will keep the SSL certificate
inside the www folder of the app. This is done specifically because this folder is copied to the image
when we build the Docker image for our app. Otherwise we will have to add copy command on the
Docker file to copy the certificate from the local machine directory to inside the image of the app.
So in the app's directory, first go inside the www folder. And here create a new folder,
give it name, HTTPS. Now double click it to go inside this newly created folder. Right click on
the empty space and select the option open in terminal. This will open the PowerShell window.
The first command to run is cleaning the previous SSL certificate from the machine.
The command to type is .net dev dash search
https-clean. Except any prompts you get, you will now see message saying HTTPS development
certificate successfully removed from the machine. We will now create a new SSL certificate.
The command to run is .net dev dash search
https-epnowstate the SSL certificate name which can be anything. I'm saying it esp.app.pfx. Then type
dash p and give the password for the certificate type my pass 1 2 3. So the password can be anything.
After that type dash dash trust this tells the machine to cross the development certificate which
we have created. Click enter. This will create the certificate and also tell the machine
to trust it. You will now see a message saying the HTTPS developer certificate was generated
successfully and is trusted. Now we have to rebuild the image so that the HTTPS folder inside
www folder is copied to the image. So we move to the folder where our docker file is an open a
PowerShell window. Now type the command
dash enter. We have to wait for someone to 2 minutes for the image to get build.
Okay the image building is completed. Now open docker desktop and remove any previous
we created container for this image. We will be creating a new container for this image.
Now it's time to run the docker command and spin a new container. We will be using environment
variable to configure the esp.net for app running from the container. So let's open the command prompt
and here we will start with the docker and command. So this command is quite big and luckily
I have saved this command on a node pad and also provide you to download this command from the
lecture itself. So this is the old command which we have to run. I copy this command and then
I paste it on the PowerShell. So let me explain this command. This is the docker run
and then be specified the name of the container fdsp. After that with dash p we give the port
mapping 5001 of the host port to 8080 of the container. And then another dash p port mapping flag
p give 4001 colon 8081, 4001 host port and 8081 until now port 8080 and 8080 1002 ports
of the containers that are open and you will get these ports in 50 docker file.
There it is the docker file of the app and use the port 8080 8081 ports are given here.
So next dash p stands for environment variable. We said the environment variable
tsp net core underscore urls to configure the two urls which are the HTTPs 8081 and HTTP80 80.
After that another environment variable of asp net core underscore the HTTPs underscore port
and here he gave the HTTPs port which is 4001 and you can see 4001 is mapped to 8021 of the container.
So 4001 of the host port will be the HTTPs port. After that another variable
asp net core underscore cross curl underscore underscore certificates and the score underscore
default underscore underscore password equal to the password which we set to create the SSL certificate
which is my pass 123. After that another environment variable asp net 4 underscore cross curl underscore
underscore certificates underscore underscore default underscore underscore part here he gave the
part of the SSL certificate inside the container which is the full part slash apps slash
w w w groups slash HTTPs and then the name of the SSL which is asp net app dot tfx and then after that
every day which is the name of the image. Now click enter to run this command
and here it is now listening on 8081. So we can now straight away open the 4001 port
to access the container on HTTPs. This is the browser and local host
4001 and here the app is opening extremely well in our browser P this item it is showing HTTPs
you click on it connection is secured and you click security connection is secured
certificate is valid. So our HTTPs certificate is applied and what we can do is now we can copy
this URL and paste it on here you will see HTTPs colon slash last 4 local host
colon 4001. So this HTTPs is now working properly on our Docker container. So we have completed
applying HTTPs on our ESP dot net core website in the same way you can apply SSL certificate
on your real world apps SSL certificate you can buy from websites like GoDaddy or get a free certificate
from let's encrypt and apply them in the same way I have shown you. Let's find the SSL certificate
inside the container it is inside the HTTPs folder. So in Docker desktop
this is the container inside the XEC you type ls and you will see www root folder
go inside this folder ICT www root and then type ls. So you will find this folder HTTPS
now go inside this it's c th tps and then type ls and here it is our SSL certificate inside the
contain other.